today i'm going to talk about the top
five programming myths that stop people
from learning how to program and that
make junior developers feel like they
are not good enough i used to believe
all these myths before and it really
slowed my progress
the first one is
everybody can learn to program
this one it's a lie
this one is a lie that many companies
tell you because they want to sell you
courses and books and bootcamps and
videos and it's not true people keep
saying that everybody can program
because programming is easy and fun and
that anybody can do it when it's not
true not everybody can do that
it's not going to be enjoyable for
everybody and it's not going to be a
career path for everybody
as a teacher i can honestly tell you
that there are some people that are just
not good or they're just not made for
programming just like i am not made to
dance ballet
some people are just different and
that's okay
saying that everybody can be a
programmer is like saying that anybody
can be a painter now we can all take
paint and put it on the canvas but that
doesn't mean that we are going to be
good at mixing colors or proportions or
our shadows and most of us are not going
to enjoy painting i hate
painting you need to enjoy logical
thinking and problem solving and also
you need to be okay with the fact that
most of the time spent programming is
frustrating is lonely not socializing in
front of a computer feeling like you are
an idiot because your code doesn't work
at 3am in the morning
this is why if you ask programmers if
they really enjoy
programming per se they will say no
programming per se it's very very
frustrating boring annoying whatever you
want to call it but what you will see is
that programmers enjoy programming
because of the result because of what
happens when you finish what happens
when you push through that frustration
and your code is finally there
programming is not for everyone
programming can be painful can be
frustrating everybody should know this
but also it's worth it
number two programming is memorization
beginners approach programming the same
way that they approach studying for an
exam in college where it's all about
remembering but not understanding this
is especially true in korea where
everything is focused on the result on
the exam rather than on the process
programming is the opposite first you
need to understand the concepts and then
you get to remember them it is not about
memorization whatsoever to make a great
piece of software you do not need to
remember all the keywords on the
programming language or whatever you're
using you need to logically understand
the problem that you need to solve and
what tools you have available so then
you can make use of the tools to fix it
most programmers do not remember
anything most programmers google at all
times senior programmers are not seniors
because they remember everything i never
use google senior programmers code less
and make more money than juniors because
they just have a better view and
understanding of all the systems and all
the landscapes of the software
development world if you want to be a
good programmer don't try to memorize
try to gain understanding first
number three is you gotta be a genius to
be a programmer
this one is a big one because of what we
see on the movies most of the time is
some like kind of wizard kit that is on
the screen typing really fast never
making any mistakes and just hacking
into the white house in the united
states now this is not what a good
programmer is or what a good hacker even
is this meet is the one that hits
hardest for junior programmers that feel
like they are not good enough they don't
feel ready to ask for a job so they keep
studying and studying and studying and
studying and this especially happens in
korea where everyone wants to be at the
top and being at the middle is not good
enough and actually you don't need to be
a genius to program they're just okay
programmers they are the average they
are good enough decent good enough
okay programmer is what most of us are
you don't have to be a genius programmer
to be able to get a job to start your
own company you can just be good enough
and that is okay in the programming
world
number four is programmers are talented
if you know how to program is because
you have a talent that god gave you or
something now i'm a firm believer that
discipline beats
talent
sure maybe there are some people that
are better at computers there are some
people that maybe will understand
something like distributed cloud
database systems faster if i explain to
them but programming is not a game of
talent programming is a game of
persistence
programming is basically saying okay
i'm not going to go to sleep until i fix
this function i am going to find this
bug i'm not gonna get angry and i'm
going to read and do everything again
what it takes to be a programmer is not
talent what takes to be a programmer is
not giving up programming is a constant
fight with the machine
that's how you win you win by not giving
up you don't win with talent
if you have focus if you are disciplined
if you are patient
you are going to be a better programmer
that somebody else that has a talent but
cannot focus
number five you need to be good at math
the reason why i put this one here is
because many people make it look like
math and being good at math is a
requirement to learn to program and that
is not true
now it's not a requirement but
it helps if you don't like math can you
still learn to program yes what can you
do if you suck at math you can do
websites front-ends back-ends databases
full stack you can do ios apps android
apps even some many maybe some video
games as well but
you're going to have a ceiling over your
head you're going to have some limits
for example you won't be able to do
something like a physics engine or
create machine learning models or work
with something like self-driving cars or
maybe even some stock exchange
automation now if you want to do these
things you are going to need math if you
want to do the sort of things that tony
stark would do you need math i socket
math and i'm happy that i'm never going
to build a self-driving car i don't care
about building a self-driving car so i'm
happy done
all right that was the top five mids
programming is not for everyone
programming is not memorization not only
geniuses can program programming is not
a talent game and if you suck at math
you can still be a programmer thank you
so much for watching this video thank
you so much for listening to me for
leaving comments for leaving a like let
me know what you think is the myth
number six on the comments we're so
close to 100k thank you so much for your
support you know i sang hello very very
very much and as always comes up
which programming language should i
start with
now this question is very hard to answer
correctly the reason why is because when
you ask me that question i don't know
you i don't know what you want
i don't know what you want to build so
if i tell you oh just learn
python html css i will be robbing you of
an explanation that you deserve in a
background that you need to understand
i'm going to answer you with giving you
five programming languages the more
popular ones
why are they used if you learn them
where are you gonna get where are you
gonna go
the first one we start with is c and c
plus plus c is a programming language
designed for a very very low level
performance very very very very close to
the machine
so for example you can use c to program
aircons or smart tvs or smart fridges
stuff like that something that has a
little bit of yes programming but it
doesn't have lots of memory also if you
learn cnc plus plus
most likely you're also going to find a
job in those big companies or
enterprises that have a make softwares
that require performance for example
you're going to end up working a project
like photoshop or premiere pro like in a
company like adobe that you have to make
software that really needs performance
next programming language java java is
very popular in korea and most of the
time java is very popular in
corporations government banks and all
that stuff nowadays is used to build
enterprise web applications if you learn
java you're 100 gonna get a job there's
many many jobs for java they are not
most of the time in very fast moving
startups java is usually used by
enterprise as a set or when you need to
integrate with older legacy systems so
some banks are in java most governments
are in java company that integrates with
this kind of services then you're going
to need java also if you learn java you
are going to be able to program android
applications so if you want to be like
an enterprise developer do you know that
you have a job and to have a safe job in
an environment that doesn't move as fast
as for example front-end development
then java is for you also if you want to
be
a android developer 100 and you love
android then java is the place for you
next one python i think the easiest
choice for a beginner and the reason why
i say this is because python is very
very very very multi-purpose for example
in python you can
find how to hack computers which is how
i learned
also with python you can do machine
learning also with python you can do
data science also in python you can do
data visualization also with python you
can do
scraping the internet also you can build
websites there's many as you can see you
can do many many many things a beginner
friendly language is not as ugly as java
and it's not as ugly as c
you need to remember that the closer the
language is to the system the lower
level the more ugly it is python is a
very pretty language to read and that's
why beginners like it so much because it
doesn't scare you at the beginning like
c if you see c
oh my god what that okay javascript but
let's make one programming language
let's call it html css and javascript if
you want to build websites and that is
the main focus of what you want to learn
to program then go for html css and
javascript that is how you start making
websites some people will tell you oh if
you want to make a website then go for
python because python makes websites as
well yes you can make a website with
python the difference is that with html
css and javascript you learn
by building something that is visually
attractive for you
and also you learn how the web works
from the ground up
from the from nothing to everything so
when you want to become a web developer
and if that's what you want to do then
html css and javascript now also if you
learn javascript and you like it a lot
you're going to be able to build very to
build many dynamic websites you can also
make some ios android applications you
can also program the back-end now
javascript is also kind of multi-purpose
like python is but javascript is very
old and
php is to build backends you can build
backends with php and php runs
everywhere
most of the internet runs on php why
because there is this thing called
wordpress wordpress runs with php and
many websites use wordpress for many
many many things
also php is uh stable the community is
big
i don't usually use it that much i
learned it before but for me it's not
it's not my thing i prefer python or
node.js but also if you learn php and
you want to be able to do stuff for
wordpress if you want to be able to do
stuff for things like magento
or drupal stuff like that like content
management systems then php is your guy
all right my people that's it so now
it's your turn ask yourself the question
what do you want to build
and then
choose right start with why first know
yourself and then all the answers will
be in front of you thank you for
watching let me know what you think
about this video i know many people are
going to disagree many people are going
to agree please comment and ask me more
questions i'm very very happy that i'm
getting more and more and more questions
every day no question is stupid all
questions i love thank you again for
watching don't forget to be happy eat
kimchi and sang yup sal bye
today i want to talk to you about the
process that i follow when i'm learning
a new programming language and that's
because nowadays i'm very interested in
go and many people have been asking me
how did i learn go did i take a course
did i watch a video did i read a book
what did i do so that's what i want to
talk about on this video and this
process that i'm going to describe has
helped me learn many languages and many
frameworks over the years so that's what
i want to share that with you
now first we need to answer the question
why should you as a developer that
already have a job as developer how
should why should you learn a new
language what's the point well if you
are a developer let's say you're a
python developer
and you learn a new language what's
going to happen is that your python code
is going to improve for example when i
was writing javascript most of the time
and then i went to learn haskell and i
came back from learning haskell
my javascript code was so much better
because of that because learning haskell
i learned new ways of doing things i
learned new philosophies i learned how
to structure the code in a different way
because of the haskell rules and then
when i brought that into javascript my
code was way better because of that so
when you learn any new programming
language any new technology those things
have new philosophies new patterns new
structures new whatever and that helps
you when you bring those concepts back
to your main programming language so if
you're a python developer and you go and
learn rust you might find something that
you like from rust and that you can
bring into python and that means that
you will become just a better developer
overall
so the first thing i do when i'm
learning a new language is i go to the
documentation on the documentation i
find out why did they create the
language what is the philosophy of the
language what is the best use case who
is using the language and also the
community the creators all that is there
so i go immediately to the documentation
then i try to understand and remember
the syntax of the language so i need to
find out if the language has parentheses
or square brackets or curly braces comma
no comma all that i get that done as
fast as i can
then what i do is i try to find
equivalences equivalences taking
knowledge that you already know on your
main language and trying to take that
into your new language so for example
this is how you make a function on
python how do you make a function on go
i try to find that out
this is a variable on python how do i
make a variable in go this is how you
make a conditional in python how do i
make a conditional angle i try to make
these associations these analogies
because the brain
works so much better when learning
something that is related to what you
already know once i'm done with the
equivalences function function variable
variable object object
once i have that in my brain i
immediately go and start writing code
the most important thing is that you
need to write code as fast as possible
don't waste time looking at tutorials
don't waste time reading more about the
language write code now what code do i
write i don't write amazing things at
the beginning i just write the
equivalences i create a variable on that
language i create a function on that
language i create a conditional a loop
all that on the language so i'm familiar
with writing on the new syntax
once i'm done writing all those old
concepts in a new language what i do is
i go for tutorials the thing with
tutorials is i felt like i was just
copying code from the songs i didn't
feel like i learned anything i just felt
like i was just copy pasting code so now
what i do instead is that i take on a
tutorial or open source project or
whatever
break it down and then put it back
together that's what i do now i remove
one part remove another part and just
break it down understanding what
happened and then
i tried to put it in together again
these kind of things help me understand
more because now it feels like the code
is mine because it feels like i can take
it apart and i can put it back in
together and then
once i'm done breaking and fixing other
people's code
what i do is i start writing my own code
i start creating my own project and this
is when beginners have a problem and is
that they start with projects then they
have never built before so they say okay
i'm learning go i want to make a chatbot
and then you tell okay have you made a
chatbot before no
and that's a problem when you want to
make a project on a new programming
language and also you have never made
that project before you have to find out
two things first you have to figure out
how to make the project logically
and then you have to write that down on
a new programming language and that is
an impossible task
what i do instead is that i
take projects that i already built
and i turn them
into the new programming language but
the logic will be the same and this
allows me to focus on learning the new
programming language instead of also
having to figure out the logic of my new
project i take a to-do list that i built
on
javascript and i make a to-do list in
react then i take a to-do list in react
and i make a to-do list on view so for
example and by the way we are launching
a new course today of go in the new go
course what i do is that i take a python
project that i built before and i turn
it into go so you build things that you
already know on a language that you
don't know and that's the key for me
[Music]
thank you for watching that's it for
this video i hope that you can get any
of this advice and i hope that i can
help you learn programming languages
faster like i said we are launching the
go course today is finally here so go
and check it out i know many people have
waited for that so i really try my best
to make a very nice sexy free course so
thank you so much for your support it's
finally here i delivered i kept my word
i'm sorry it was so late but i've been
very busy but there it is so go and
check it out click on the link on the
description and as always don't forget
to be happy don't forget to eat kimchi
don't forget to be nice to people today
take care of the virus wear your mask
wash your hands and as always san angelo
bye-bye
nicolas
today we are going to talk about why
java is named java why ruby is named
ruby one python is named python
let's get started with java java was
first going to be called oak like the
tree because that tree was growing
outside of the offices of one of the
designers of java the problem was that
they couldn't name it oak because it was
already trademarked there was already a
company with that name so the lawyers
came back to the team and they told them
to come up with a new name he up
and what the team was is that they went
into a room and they started to do
brainstorming of some names and some of
the options that they got were for
example dna or silk or wrl which means
web runner language and thankfully they
arrived to the name jab
java is also a kind of coffee and it's
also an island on indonesia so that's
why you see that the logo of java is
like a hot cup of coffee
then we got a programming language
called kotlin
kotlin is directly inspired by java and
is actually like an improvement of java
kotlin is made by a company called jet
brains that company is a russian company
and because java is also an island on
indonesia
jetbrains named their programming
language after a russian island
[Music]
then we have javascript javascript was
first called mocha like the coffee plus
chocolate preparation but then they
switched from mocha to live script and
at that point in time java was super
super popular so what they wanted to do
was like a marketing trick and they
changed the name livescript to
javascript hoping that people thought
that javascript was going to complement
java and they just wanted developers to
basically be interested in javascript
and it looks like it worked because now
javascript is one of the most popular
languages
c was named after a programming language
called b because many of the things that
b had c got influenced by then we got c
plus plus on the programming word plus
plus means increment so basically is
like an increment of c so c plus plus
means like c plus one and then we got c
sharp on the music word when you play a
note and you put the sharp that also
means an increment on the note it should
be played a tone higher so on the music
word sharp is an increment on the
programming word plus plus is an
increment and if you look at it c sharp
is basically c with four plus plus plus
ruby is a programming language created
by an ilbon saram and this programming
language was directly inspired by pearl
pearl is like a precious stone and is
also another programming language so
what the creator of ruby wanted to do
was also name his language like a
precious stone so he chose ruby
python was named after a comedy show
called monty python people think that
python was named after a snake because
the creator of python loves snakes is
not true the creator of python loved a
comedy show called monty python
and now if you're wondering go was
created by google so that's why we have
the go part the name of the mascot of go
is and he is an animal called gopper
and rust was also named after a fungus
because the designer of ross kind of
liked those sort of organisms so that's
why he made it nothing much on that name
not much story behind it
that's it for this video thank you so
much for watching let me know on the
comments if you made a programming
language what name would you choose
thank you for watching again don't
forget to be happy don't forget to eat
kimchi salan hello and hanzo nida bye
bye
today we are going to talk about the
difference between c
c plus and c sharp because they share
the same c on the name so sometimes we
can get confused so
c c is a language that was created 47
years ago it's a very long time ago c
has influenced languages such as java
javascript python
php
go among many others so is is seen as a
very important language in the history
of computer programming c was created as
i said 47 years ago that means that back
then the computers weren't so fast as
they are right now so c is very good
at
working on machines that don't have a
lot of resources and being as close to
the hardware as possible for example
things that are made on sea
the
mars rover curiosity that thing that was
sent to space
to mars that landed in mars that has
been moving around taking photos of mars
and sending them back to nasa over
satellite and the space or whatever that
is that thing is programmed in 2.5
million lines of sea code that is just
raw c code because the mass rover that
little tiny robot not little but that
robot doesn't have a lot of memory
doesn't have a lot of processing power
so we need as much speed as we can in as
little space as possible that is c now
what is c plus plus c plus plus is just
like c
but with classes and even the creator of
c plus plus says that c
is obsolete when he created c plus plus
he intended c plus plus to be like a
superset of c a superset is a language
that extends another language so for
example javascript and typescript
typescript extends javascript because it
adds
types
javascript doesn't have types typescript
is just like javascript but it has a new
addition an extension
because it has types
c plus plus and c
was supposed to be seen as a c
with classes because c does not support
classes object-oriented programming that
is very very important when you are
organizing large code bases this is what
the creator of c plus plus says the
creator of c plus plus says that he
intended c plus plus to be the
replacement of c and that they should
have been used one language all together
unification because they are so similar
except that the the c plus plus has
classes among all the details now what
is program on c plus plus i don't think
that there is a difference in speed
whatsoever and there is not a difference
in how close you can be on the hardware
but people sometimes choose c plus plus
because they enjoy the object oriented
programming now c sharp c sharp is a
whole different beast c sharp is more
similar to java than it is to c plus c
sharp is like
the java of microsoft it's a programming
language that was created for the
enterprise applications microsoft spent
thousands of dollars and hours making
this language because c-sharp works on
the net ecosystem java and oracle
does one thing c-sharp.net
that's the other thing there's like two
teams for the corporate and the
enterprise in korea i've seen that java
rules the most but outside of korea
mostly in the us and in europe c-sharp
and net they roll the most also c-sharp
is very powerful you can make back-ends
you can make front-ends you can make ios
applications and
nowadays c-sharp has seen a very high
increase in usage because of unity 3d in
c-sharp if you if you learn c-sharp you
can make
video games for xbox playstation uh
computer ios android and even web
with unity 3d unity3d is a video game
engine so the thing is that c sharp is
not as fast as c plus plus because on c
sharp
we don't do stuff manually the compiler
and the program help us doing some stuff
on c plus plus and on c we have to do
things manually because c is more of a
lower level language so people say that
on c plus plus the computer runs fast
and on c sharp the developer runs fast i
think c sharp is a language where many
developers are very satisfied with it
because it just has a lot of developer
speed you can do lots of stuff and you
don't have to do things manually as with
c plus plus c sharp is more similar to
java so for example if you know
javascript typescript or java you can go
into c sharp really really quickly and
it will take you maybe one or two weeks
to get ready and go for it i might in my
case i program on c sharp because i like
to make stuff in unity 3d so that's why
i use sharp i never work with microsoft
any kind of microsoft enterprise but
it's a very it's a very good career
choice to learn c sharp if you want to
work with the enterprise and the net
ecosystem all right so that's it very
small systems speed speed speed c-sharp
is more of an enterprise thing c-sharp
looks like looks more like java than it
looks like c and it's enterprise
developer speed on c sharp is higher
computer speed on c and c plus plus is
higher so there are different beasts for
different things most companies use c
sharp or java and then when they need
actual speed they go to first year c
plus
thank you for watching let me know what
you think of this video i really really
appreciate all your support and all your
comments i sat on hello very much and
that's it see you on the next one don't
forget to be happy today smile and eat
kimchi bye bye
on this video i'm going to talk about
why python is such a popular programming
language what are the best three uses of
python and how you can start learning it
this year python passed java on the
stack overflow developers survey as the
most popular programming language last
year it passed c-sharp and the year
before that it passed php python has
been growing exponentially and really
fast these last maybe four to five years
but why python is not popular only
because of one reason python is popular
because of a combination of many reasons
the first one is that python code looks
almost like english code
is very close to the human language even
if you don't know any computer science
even if you don't know how to program
but you read some python code you will
chances are be able to understand what's
going on because it really looks like
almost like just human normal language
and that's something that developers
that are starting love and it's
something that developers that are
experienced also love another reason why
it's so popular is because python keeps
your options open it doesn't put you on
any box for example if you don't know
what you want to do maybe you want to
try web development maybe you want to
try ai maybe you want to try data
science but you don't know maybe you
want to do some security and hacking and
all that python is the perfect language
for a person like that because you don't
have to go into a box of back-end
developer ai developer machine learning
developer you do not have to do that
because if you're in python you can move
between all those disciplines as much as
you want without having to learn a new
language so if you're having a hard time
choosing which area of technology you
want to work learning python is just
going to be the perfect choice because
it will allow you to just try a little
bit see if you like it and if you don't
move on without learning another
programming language and that brings me
to my reason number three the community
in python is unbelievably
awesome is very big and very diverse
because we have people from everywhere
on the industry we have people that are
machine learning engineers we have web
developers we have hackers we have data
scientists we have mathematicians we
have finance we have so many people on
this community and they are all coming
with their own tools with their own open
source so there are more tutorials there
are more courses there are more videos
there are more questions there are more
answers and it's just when you're
starting as a beginner seeing such huge
community will help you a lot with
python you can do almost anything
because it's a multi-purpose programming
language but the three things where
python is used the most is on web
development
ai machine learning and data science
and scripting so web development with
python you can make a backend for an
application you can make an api you can
you can make a whole website using
python uh for example instagram uses
python pinterest uses python reddit uses
python on their backend the second one
is machine learning many people are
making amazing libraries for machine
learning such as for example google is
giving us tensorflow we also have cadas
we also have panda we have so many
libraries for machine learning that if
you want to get into machine learning
that is the way python is really really
used by the industry into trained models
supervised learning unsupervised
learning all that it's on python now the
third use
of python is scripting and scripting
basically means
automating the boring stuff for example
if you're an office worker and you need
to maybe
change the name of 1000 pdfs you can
make a simple python script that will do
that in one second whether you will take
maybe 30 minutes or an hour doing it
scripting allows you to just use python
for small tasks that you might you might
face on your workplace so for example
scripting can be something that people
like accountants lawyers students
anybody can learn how to descript them
with python because it will just improve
their life they don't have to become a
developer they don't have to be a
programmer but they can just learn a
little bit so they can automate the
boring office work stuff and this is
something where python shines a lot
having said that how can you start
learning python well on this video we
are launching a free python course for
absolute beginners where we are doing to
do some of this optimization of boring
work in the case of the course that we
just uploaded we are going to go to
websites that offer jobs and we are
going to take those jobs and we are
going to put them on an excel sheet for
more organization it's going to be a
simple project where you're going to
learn how to extract data from different
websites and how to put them all inside
of an excel
thank you for watching let me know what
you think of this video i hope that you
go and take our free course it's free
free free as always don't forget to be
happy don't forget to eat kimchi and
that's it thank you bye-bye
today we're going to learn why a
programming language like python is
slower
than a programming language like c by by
the way i said slower i didn't say slow
slower all programming languages are
very fast okay they do things fast in
our computer faster than our brains can
do it so they're all fast some of them
are slow work doesn't mean they're slow
computers do not understand humans
computers speak zeros and ones
[Music]
now humans we speak code
the main source of nutrition programming
language so we say for example if else
function variable we do all that stuff
all right so you can see we speak
different languages code is here zeros
and ones are here two different
languages now
there has to be a way of translating if
else function whatever two zeros and
ones that process in the middle is
called compilation or
interpretation
let me give you an example of
interpretation and an example of
compilation so right now i'm in turkey
here they speak turkish i speak english
so i don't understand if i'm walking
down the street and some turkish person
comes to me
and they start speaking
i wouldn't know what interpretation
would do is that i will have literally
my friend here an interpreter that will
be speaking to my ear and translating
everything to english
i am getting some turkish message here
and my friend is immediately translating
everything into english to my ear that
is interpretation it happens in real
time
now what is compilation compilation
doesn't happen in real time compilation
first my friend will go
my friend will listen to them
and then once my friend
understands the sentences once my friend
understands what they mean my friend
will translate the entire message to me
that is compilation versus
interpretation one of them
interpretation is done in real time and
the other one is done not in real time
that that's what makes a programming
language slower and faster for example
python is interpreted nc is compiled
so on python there is always a person
here
speaking to the computer the zeros and
the ones that he needs to get for every
line and that could be slow that could
be a slow process because there is
always a middleman in the middle between
your python code and the zeros and ones
now when you work with something like c
is compiled that means that after you
finish your program you're going to
press
compile the compiler will translate all
your code into zeros and once and then
you will be able to open your program
and of course it will be faster because
the there is no middleman there your
code will become zeros and once
immediately and when you open the
program you'll be serious in once there
is no middleman there now another
example of this of why the difference
between interpretation versus
compilation if my friend is my
interpreter right here and the turkish
person maybe he speaks a word that my
friend doesn't know
my friend would say oop sorry i don't
know
and then we're gonna be lost
right that would be interpretation now
if it was compilation and that turkish
person speaks to my friend some word he
doesn't know my friend would stop it and
say like hey i don't know that word
change the word because i need to
translate that and i don't understand
that word that would be the same thing
in compilation and interpretation
when we have errors for example on
python for example or even javascript
because it's an interpreted language
and it happens in real time my code
might have some errors and
i might
don't know about these errors until they
happen and that is not good at all i
want to know about my errors before they
happen so i can fix them but because
it's interpreted it will be real time
now if it's compiled for example when
you have a mistake on c
or any compiled language and you try to
compile your program c will tell you
wait one second hold on that doesn't
work i don't understand that fix it so
you know that once you compile your
software using the c compiler for
example you know that that code doesn't
have errors
because the compiler
approved it basically of course if you
have an interpreter that is a middleman
if you don't you have all the power of
the zeros and ones and you can access
even deeper parts of the computers
without a middleman that might be a
little bit slow so that's it i know i
made big generalizations on this video
if you are already a programmer and
you're experimented and you like the
theory then i know you're gonna disagree
with some things that i said but i allow
myself to generalize because that's easy
to explain concepts i know
sometimes you can make python a compile
language there are ways of doing that
but generally python is interpreted and
c is compiled
all right thank you for watching i hope
that you understood a little bit better
about how we communicate with computers
and i hope that you like my example of
my turkeys and my translator and let me
know what you think let me know if you
like this video share it with your
friends and don't worry about speed
really it's not a big deal to choose the
fastest programming language in the
world not a big deal uh that's it thank
you very much thank you for watching see
you in the next one eat kimchi be happy
and bye
nicolas
today i am going to talk about the most
popular programming language in the
world
this programming language is javascript
even if you hate it or you love it
there's nothing we can do javascript is
the most popular one now javascript is
not only a language that we use to make
websites with react or vue.js there is
so much more that you can do with
javascript especially if you are a
designer or a creative artist or a media
person or a web publisher it is so much
more than you can do with javascript and
that's why on this video i am going to
talk about the other uses of javascript
apart from website making
first you can make hybrid apps or
cross-platform apps i know you heard
about hybrid apps before in
cross-platform apps on this channel so
we're not going to talk too much about
that but if you want to make hybrid apps
with javascript look into something
called ionic or if you want to build
some cross platform apps look into
something called react native hybrid
technology is used by amazon for example
their ios and android application is
based on web and hybrid views also the
wechat ecosystem is built around hybrid
apps and the react native side people
like discord tencent pinterest in some
parts of facebook and instagram are
built using react native so if you want
to be an app developer and you know
javascript you can get started right
away
number two
desktop software for mac windows and
linux if you want to make software for
the desktop you can do that using
javascript and electron electron takes
html css and javascript compiles it and
it will give you
a windows linux or mac os
software ready to install in the
computer it's an awesome awesome tool
and
many of the big big projects that i
think that you already use are using
electron for example visual studio code
the most popular text editor in the
world is built using html css javascript
and electron also slack for desktop
skype github desktop and also atom
another
text editor among hundreds of thousands
of other applications so if you want to
make desktop applications that your
users can install
go ahead all you need to know is html
css and javascript
now if you're a little bit more creative
and you like video games you can make 2d
video games with javascript really
really easy you can use things like
phaser.js or impact js you can make
awesome 2d video games you don't have to
write anything of the physics because
those engines already come with a
javascript physics engine and you can
use the graphic cards power of the
browser also using node.js and soccer io
you can make these 2d video games
interactive and multiplayers there is
one really good example of a multiplayer
to the javascript video game called
wanderers.io
go check it out it's real time
multiplayer 2d a strategy game using
only javascript amazing
now this is the part that excites me the
most
3d
vr and ar stuff using for example three
js you can build awesome 3d video games
running on the browser you can create
maybe really cool interactive websites
for maybe advertising portfolios
e-commerce or just crazy 3d artistic
experiments for example the band arcade
fire has a couple of
video clips that are on the browser so
with your camera you can interact with
the video clip or with the mouse you can
even modify the way the video changes
and they use geolocation they use canvas
they use javascript they use webgl they
use so many things to make like a more
immersive experience of the video clip
but on the browser heraclous is also a
beautiful 3 js
video game that combines sound video
textures and story all on the browser it
looks amazing it's really really
beautiful and it's all done with
javascript for example you could also
make a really interesting and
interactive e-commerce website to sell
some stuff but combined with 3d the best
example i can think of is something
called campo ale comete which is like
italian winery but when you go to the
website it looks almost like a video
game and you don't realize that they are
sending you wine it's a really nice
experience when you want to buy
something using a frame or arjs you can
also build websites that use the camera
and sensors of the device to build
beards to a reality or augmented reality
websites you can make vr video games on
the browser using ar that connect for
example to the oculus so that your users
can play on the browser or you can make
a website for example a shopping mall
that shows the users directions using ar
everything running on a website without
having to download any app also very few
people know this but you can do machine
learning on the browser for example you
can make a 2d or 3d video game and you
can use tensorflow.js to maybe give the
enemies actual artificial intelligence
that is really really mind-blowing
and that's it
as you can see there is so much more
than you can do with javascript apart
from just
boring websites you can make
applications desktop software video
games 3d experiences vr ar websites the
possibilities are endless if you are a
javascript developer already i hope that
i inspire you to go and build your own
video game or desktop app if you are not
a javascript developer but you want to
learn then go to our website we have a
free javascript course for absolute
beginners so you can get started
learning javascript and you can build
amazing crazy things like the ones i
showed you on this video thank you so
much for all your comments in the golang
video i really really appreciate it i'm
already working on the course and that's
it thank you so much as always don't
forget to be happy don't forget to go
build amazing beautiful things don't
forget to eat kimchi that's it
today we're going to talk about how we
can become better programmers by
changing the way that we see mistakes
and errors in our code a good programmer
is not a programmer that doesn't do any
mistakes or that always writes the
perfect code without any syntax errors
that is not what a good programmer is
okay that shouldn't discourage you from
becoming a programmer if you make many
mistakes you shouldn't feel like maybe
this is not for me no that is not what a
good programmer is what a good
programmer is is a programmer that makes
errors and learns and grows from those
mistakes if you make a mistake and you
grow from it that's when you become a
good programmer okay so it doesn't mean
that making mistakes is bad and we
should try to never make any mistakes no
we should learn from our mistakes and we
should try to never make the same
mistake twice that's how we become a
good programmer okay so tip number one
of mindset change when we see an error
in our screen
[Music]
we shouldn't remove ourselves from the
problem and what that means is that i've
seen people sometimes including myself
when i see an error on the screen of
some program that i made i think to
myself and i know many people think to
themselves and they show it on the
comments on my courses and they say oh
the code doesn't work as if it's
something external from them so they say
the code is not working as if the
computer or the code have a problem and
what i say to this is actually no we
made that mistake the code is not
working because of me so i should take
ownership of that mistake i should say i
caused that problem and when i say that
i now can fix the problem if you are the
cause of the problem then also you can
be the solution of that problem okay but
if we just leave all responsibility
behind and we say oh the code doesn't
work like the code over there should be
working but it's not no
my code is not working because of me
okay so we need to own our mistakes
tip number two
[Music]
is we should stop trying to fix errors
and i know that sounds crazy for me to
say maybe you are saying like what we
shouldn't fix an error no what i'm
saying is we should understand where the
errors come from okay if you're just
trying to fix errors whenever they
happen you are just a fireman trying to
put out fires okay but the fire is going
to come back again eventually what we
want as programmers is we need to
understand
why did this error happen and if we
understand the cause of the error then
in the future we are very less likely
that we are going to repeat the same
mistake because now we understand why
the error happens so now we know how we
can fix it but most importantly why it
happened because i know how it feels
when we are working and we see an error
and we see a red alert saying does not
work wrong code we want to do is just
say how can i fix it so we go to google
we ask our friends we go to the slack
channel and we say how can i fix this
error we shouldn't do that anymore what
we should do is what is the cause of
this error and then also if somebody
asks you how can i fix this error what
you should say is not i'm not going to
tell you how to fix it i'm going to tell
you what was the cause if we understand
the cause we are less likely to repeat
the error again so let's try to
understand the cause instead of just
trying to make all the errors disappear
number three
[Music]
it's very easy when we see an error to
freak out and basically say oh it's not
working again what happened and go back
and look at the code and google and ask
our friends it's very easy to do all
those things right but you know why it's
easier than that reading the error
message and i know it sounds crazy and
it's something so obvious but even i
forget to this day when something
doesn't work i immediately go back to my
code and try to find a problem with my
code actually if you look at the error
message
most of the fixes of the way to fix of
the source of the error of the
explanation of the error is on the error
message so sometimes i get people to ask
me why is this error happening and i say
just read the error message it's
literally there they're telling you what
you did wrong and they're telling you
how you can fix it
so again
it's something so simple and so basic
and so obvious but we forget about it
and i forget about it i also get
stressed i also want to make the error
disappear i also want to be like what
happened i want to go back and look at
my code well actually all i should do is
look at the error message and read it it
might look intimidating because error
messages don't look nice when you're a
programmer it's a bunch of code and then
there is one line that says exactly what
you need to do to fix it so we can look
at it and if we don't be careful and we
don't read them carefully it just looks
like gibberish but it's actually
something there so let's look at the
error messages a little bit more closely
because the people that make the
libraries that we use the people that
make the programs that we use they put
those error messages there for a reason
they tell you how to fix it they'll tell
you where the source is
thank you so much for watching let me
know what you think on the comments and
please tell me
how do you deal with errors and is there
any technique any tip that you can share
with the community let us know on the
comments thank you so much for watching
again i appreciate your support i
appreciate your likes don't forget to be
happy don't forget to eat kimchi
kamzamida
as you know i am a self-taught software
developer and i believe that you don't
need to go to college you don't need to
go to university to be able to become a
programmer and to be able to get a job
on a company but having said that
learning to program by yourself online
is not easy there are many traps you can
fall into and there are many mistakes
that you can make that will frustrate
you and will make you waste time so on
this video our first video of 2020 i
want to talk about that i want to talk
about the mistakes and the traps that
beginners fall into when learning to
program by themselves and how you can
avoid them
mistake number one
not building anything
some people approach programming like
they approach studying for an exam in
school where they just read a book they
take some notes they memorize some
things and you're done programming is
not something that you study
programming is something that you do
it's a verb it's an action and if you're
learning to program and you're not
applying that knowledge if you are not
writing your own code then you are just
wasting your time when you're learning
to program build projects practice make
stuff from your own code don't copy your
teacher's code don't copy the book code
build things on your own but also be
careful set realistic goals it's okay to
do a dumb project like a calculator or a
small web scraper or a very tiny video
game that's also okay the point is to
always build something create
write code then you study read and
memorize write
make stuff build stuff be a maker
instead of a learner
number two is not knowing when you are
ready this happens a lot to beginners
because they feel like they haven't
learned enough yet they feel like still
they have to take one more course they
have to read one more book they have to
watch one more lecture they don't feel
ready to go and apply for a job or to
start their own company and build their
own product so how to avoid this it's
very easy go back to the point number
one of this video build
things when you build something your
eyes and your brain see a visual
representation and a result of all the
knowledge that you've been accumulating
in your head and that tells your brain
that you are ready
simple that gives you the confidence to
know hey i built that that means i am
ready usually the people that get stuck
in the always learning phase the ones
that keep buying books the ones that
keep buying courses the ones that keep
reading stuff
those are the ones that are not building
if you want to measure your knowledge if
you want to know if you know
simple go and build stuff mistake number
three
is going 100
into programming when you're going to
the gym for example you don't want to
train a hundred percent and give
everything that you've got that day why
not because you are gonna wake up the
next day feeling like because
everything hurts and you are probably
not gonna go to the gym that day or the
next day when the point is to go to the
gym every day to train every day is the
same with programming the point is to
program every day the point is to build
a habit the point is to learn
every day if you go 100 on programming
and you forget your hobbies you don't
take breaks you don't socialize you just
only programming you are gonna burn out
and you are not gonna have fun learning
which should be the number one priority
when you learn to program the point is
you should be able to have fun and you
should be able to wish to go and start
programming you should be able to be
like oh i can't wait to go and start
programming start learning that you
should enjoy you need to find the
balance for me sometimes it's an 80 20
sometimes it's a 70 30. sometimes i
don't do programming at all it just
depends on the person i'm not here to
tell you which balance but find your
balance don't go a hundred percent go
your percent
mistake number four
is
checking
boxes programming is not about checking
boxes and some people especially in
korea they want to find a list or a
roadmap of boxes to check so they want
to find a list that says okay check html
css javascript java and sql boom
you are a programmer but that just
doesn't happen programming is not a list
of boxes that you check
people don't know javascript they don't
know python we just work with it and
kind of understand it but there is never
gonna be a box to check you are never
gonna finish learning python you are
never gonna finish learning javascript
so that box right there is invisible
it's like a rainbow instead of having a
list make a list of projects that you
want to make so for example make a chat
bot make a youtube clone or a video game
now if you follow that approach the
project oriented learning what you're
going to find out is that the moment you
go and apply for a job you are going to
have a big portfolio and that is going
to get you a job faster
rather than somebody that just puts on
the resume i know js i know java and i
know sql portfolio
and resume
the person with the portfolio will
always win against the person that just
has a resume that says i know java check
number five is
have a deadline and this is something
that applies for any kind of learning
not only programming any kind of
self-paced
learning when you do it by yourself
it's very easy to see the time just go
by without seeing any results if you
don't pressure yourself because when you
don't have a deadline you don't feel the
pressure to go and study you don't feel
the pressure to go and finish something
you just you're there you are starting
programming but when do you have a
deadline do you have a commitment with
who with yourself and this is why people
go to university and this is why
university works in that sense because
in university you have grades you have
exams you have projects you have the
teacher telling you that you are gonna
fail and that keeps you on your toes
actually studying what you need to find
out is a way of pressuring yourself
maybe write your commitment on the wall
and say okay july 2020 i am gonna learn
python or tell your friends say hey if i
don't learn python by july you come
punch me in the throat or put it on
facebook or put a bet give money to
somebody i don't know find a way of
pressuring yourself because when you are
learning by yourself it's very easy to
just
yeah later because you don't have a
deadline you need to find a deadline
thank you so much for watching this
video thank you so much for your support
for your attention for listening to me i
really appreciate you watching i really
appreciate your comments i really
appreciate your likes your views your
support your subscriptions everything i
hope that i can help you in to become a
better programmer if you are making one
of these mistakes don't feel bad because
i made them all and that's what i'm
talking about
[Music]
i said angelo you very much eat kimchi
and that's it thank you see you on the
next one i'll talk to you soon bye bye
today we're going to talk about the
difference between a library and a
framework and the reason why is because
this is a question that you might get on
your next programming job interview so i
want you to be able to answer this
question because the concept is not that
hard to understand but it's very very
useful to know what the difference is
between library and framework so i'm
going to give you an example of what is
library what is framework and also what
sort of contradictions exists because of
course nothing is ever black and white
okay
[Music]
now first let me start by saying that
both libraries and frameworks are code
that somebody else wrote that we are
using in our project okay so both
external things that we use to finish
things faster the difference between
library and framework lies on a
very simple concept who is controlling
who okay
are you in control of your code are you
the one making all the choices or are
you following someone else's rules and
that basically is the whole difference
between a library and a framework do you
control the code do you control exactly
what's happening or are you following
rules okay let me give you an example
a good example of a library is jquery
jquery allows you to basically add
interactivity to a website right
now this means that when i'm working on
my website when i'm working on some code
i
will call jquery when i need jquery okay
so if i need jquery right now i will
call jquery i will use a query and then
i will keep going on my program this is
how we use libraries we use libraries
when we need them and libraries are very
easy to be replaced if i change the
query for something else
the website shouldn't break and my
project shouldn't break it shouldn't be
a big deal to replace the library
because it's just something that i'm
calling to save some time all right now
a framework is different
[Music]
because you the programmer doesn't call
the framework the framework
calls your code okay and that's very
important and that's the whole
difference between libraries and
frameworks when you work with a
framework you have to follow the
frameworks rules you are not in control
of your code you don't decide what
happens and how it happens no the
framework tells you what to do the
framework tells you where to put your
code if you want the framework to work
so the framework gives you rules the
framework gives you a structure where to
put your template where to pull your
controllers where to put your views
and if you follow those rules everything
will
are not in work
you just follow the friendliest rules
one example of a framework is the jungle
world framework the django web framework
has a lot of rules and a lot of
structure that you have to follow if you
want everything to work correctly for
example
on the jungle framework if you want to
have an admin panel you need to write
your code on the file called admin that
pi
if you want to change
any sort of url
you are going to have to go to the file
called
urls.pi and when django starts django is
going to look for a file called url.pi
and admin.pi
you are not in control of this this is a
rule that django has and now if you
follow the rules correctly you are going
to have a website with an admin panel
and with the urls working so as you can
see
never in this scenario
i called django never i just look at the
django documentation i follow the rules
i put my code on the right places and
django will load those things
everything that is a framework is
because it has some rules that we must
follow everything that is a library is
because it's something that we call when
we feel like it i call a library
but a framework calls me
and that's very important and
interesting the extension to make all
right so next time you see something
that says
library to build blah blah blah you know
that is something that you are going to
call when you need it but next time you
see something that says a framework for
building whatever you know that this is
something that comes with some rules
something that comes with opinions and
something that you are going to have to
cooperate with basically where you are
in control you just need to work under
the frameworks rules
[Music]
if you go for example to the react.js
website on the react.js website it says
that react.js is a
library
so it means that if you need to build
the ui of your application then that
means that you are going to have to call
react right in this case we are calling
react so that would make react.js a
library because we are calling it when
we need a user interface and react.js
doesn't come with any sort of opinions
it doesn't come with a folder structure
it doesn't come with a component name
doesn't come with anything
except that
react.js calls our components
so in this case react.js could be a
framework
because react.js is calling your
component react.js is telling you the
rules react.js is telling you what is
wrong and what is right and when you
write a component react calls that
component and shows it on the screen so
in this case it's a very gray area and
you can google around and see if
reactions is a framework or a library
because some people say that react.js is
a library because you call it when you
need it but also react.js could be a
framework because react.js calls our
components and react.js makes our
components interactive and react.js
gives our components a state and props
and all that this also applies to vue.js
as well
so
does it matter if react.js is a
framework or a library it doesn't really
matter because on the front end all the
lines are blurred but it's very
important that you and i know what's the
difference or at least in the theory
what's the difference between a
framework and a library in case we get
this question on an interview
so thank you for watching let me know
what you think of this video let me know
in the comments thank you again don't
forget to be happy come sammy da shannon
hello take care of yourself love
yourself
bye-bye
before i go i just wanted to let you all
know that we just published our first
book
this book is a react js book for
beginners so go and check it out if you
want to learn react.js and also the
people that buy the book are going to
get a very sexy t-shirt with a normal
coders logo and with the words clone
startups learn to code on the back i
hope you like it if you want to know
react.js this is 100 for you let me know
what you think about it on the comments
thank you for watching and bye bye
nicolas
when you want to make ios and android
applications you usually have three
options hybrid applications
cross-platform applications and native
applications which one should i choose
native
cross-platform hybrid should i learn ios
and android should i learn flutter and
react native which one
hybrid applications hybrid applications
are just websites wrapped around a web
view a web view is a window of the
browser without the navigation controls
so when you make a hybrid application
all you're doing is that you take html
css and javascript you wrap it around a
web view and you send it to the store
what i'm basically opening is a google
chrome window
without the navigation bar with your
with your html and css inside of it good
things about this is that you don't need
any native knowledge required to make an
app all you need is html css and
javascript which is an awesome thing
bad thing about this is that you have to
do everything by yourself you have to do
all the ui by yourself or the all the
buttons all the navigations because
you're basically making a website from
scratch also you do not have access to
all the power of the phone you cannot do
for example some hardcore video
processing it would be too hard to do
that on javascript because what you're
doing is just a website what you can do
on a hybrid application is get some
basic camera geolocation network
information some contacts but not as
much as maybe your application would
like if you want to make hybrid
applications look into something called
apache cordoba or funga these are the
services that wrap your html
around that webview cross-platform
applications cross-platform applications
are basically when you write some sort
of code that is not a native code but
later on gets translated into code that
ios and android can understand for
example react native all you have to
write is react code that gets compiled
into some javascript code and then ios
and android execute that javascript code
with their own javascript engine in
flutter you write dart code and that
gets compiled to cc plus plus that both
ios and android can understand and in
summary which is what c
sharp
you write c sharp code and that gets
compiled into some sort of intermediate
language that ios and android can
understand so as you can see you are not
writing native code but your code is
eventually going to these native
platforms the good things about this
method is that you only have to write
your application once and you can see it
in two platforms which is awesome
because you can reuse developer time
if i'm a react developer i can make a
react native app very very very easy for
example also if you're a dart developer
you will be able to make an ios app
android and also your website because
now we have something called flutter web
which is nice a very good thing of cross
platform development is that it attracts
many many people from many different
backgrounds maybe a back-end developer
wants to make an app or react native
maybe a java developer and what you get
is just an amazing mix of ideas
libraries tutorials and just the
community is great because
cross-platform is a very very attractive
thing for development a bad thing is
that still is not native so still
you will have some performance issues if
while you need its performance don't get
me wrong cross-platform applications are
not slow
if you use them for the right job they
are just the best solution for example
some parts of instagram run on react
native but if you do
need performance those applications
might be a little bit slow on that case
because as i told you there is a
translation step that might not allow
you to reach into the power of the phone
native development is basically just
writing ios code and android code
separately so for ios you will learn
something like swift and for android you
learn something like java or cotton good
things about this is that you have as
much power as the phone has and you can
use whatever api is available because
there's no middleman between your code
and the phone bad things about native
development is that you will have to
learn two separate platforms
ios and android you have to learn street
you have to learn java they're both
different and they do things differently
also you need to learn about xcode and
android studio both separate uh software
to create applications so it's just more
time consuming but if performance is
what you want then
maybe learning two platforms is going to
pay off in the future like maybe making
a camera app that puts a 3d
then you're going to need all the power
you can get and the power comes from
native development
that's it thank you for watching i hope
that you liked the review and i hope
that now you can make a better choice
into where and how to build your amazing
ios android idea on this video i did not
compare flutter with react native and
summary but it's a video that maybe i
will make because they are very
different they accomplish things in a
different way so let me know in the
comments if you want me to make a video
comparing flutter react native and
examining come summed it up and see you
on the next video bye-bye
today we are going to talk about ai
machine learning and deep
learning the reason why is because ai is
everywhere in the news
the government loves to put money on ai
projects ai pension capital investors
love to put money on machine learning
powered companies
air investment ai johnson and
everybody's talking about deep learning
algorithms we are going to define what
is ai what is machine learning what is
deep learning at the end i'm going to
tell you how a full stack programmer
like me that doesn't like math and that
doesn't really like calculus and all
that can get started working with
artificial intelligence and machine
learning
ai
ai is divided in two categories narrow
ai and general ai
hollywood and netflix and all the movies
are in general ai
general ai is machines that do
everything that humans do and better
that can do a general purpose ai that
can do
anything so it can talk it can learn to
play games it can communicate it can
make a judgement it can just be exactly
like a human and that is
general ai
right now in the world in the industry
we are in a narrow ai
narrow ai are machines that can only do
one thing and one thing very well where
the focus of the machine is narrow the
applications are narrow the machine can
do one thing well and one thing only an
example of narrow ai would be for
example the facebook ai at finding out
faces in photos but that's it this ai is
not able to learn how to find out
dogs in photos because it's narrow it's
gene it's narrow ai it can only do one
thing well and one thing only that's
where we are right now but now we need
to understand how we teach those ai's
here is where machine learning comes
machine learning is the way to
accomplish
ai so how do machines learn there are
many categories of machine learning but
the most famous ones
are two
on unsupervised learning and super
biased learning let's say that we are
going to make an application that
detects if a food is a hot dog or not a
hot dog
[Music]
if we did it in a supervised way what we
will do is that we will label
what a hot dog is okay a hot dog is a
sausage a hot dog is long a hot dog has
some sauce on top a hot dog
has is between a bun
that is a label we're going to label
what a hot dog is we're going to tell
the machine what a hot dog is all right
and then we are going to get millions of
photos of any kind of food we're going
to put that into the machine in the
machine
based in our labels the machine is going
to say okay this photo has 60
chance of being a hotdog so the machine
is not thinking the machine is just
telling us in a probability way with
statistics and mathematics is just
telling us this has 95 chance of being a
hot dog based on the labels that the
humans gave to the machine
one example of supervised machine
learning would be for example a music
recommendation system the user us will
label
the songs that we like so we will tell
the machine these are the songs that i
enjoy this is the kind of beat that i
enjoy this is the kind of artist that i
like next time a new song comes the
machine now has labeled data into what
is a song that nicolas likes and then
you will know if nicolas has a 90 chance
of liking this new song that's coming up
that is supervised learning humans label
the data now in unsupervised learning
the humans do not label the data so for
example to do this hot dog app what we
are going to do is that we are going to
give to the machine millions of photos
of only hot dogs we're going to give
that to the machine we're not going to
give the machine any labels and we are
going to let the machine by itself
figure out a label
that makes a hotdog so we're not going
to tell any description of a hot dog
we're just going to give the machine a
lot of hotdog photos and the machine
will figure out by itself after a lot of
time and a lot of processing power and a
lot a lot of data all right now of
course i know
this is just a very simple explanation
if you want this if you like this topic
we can talk more about it in future
videos but now i need to move on to the
last topic which is deep learning deep
learning is just a way to accomplish
machine learning machine learning is a
way to accomplish ai
deep learning is called deep learning
because it makes use of something called
neural networks
very smart scientists very smart
mathematicians and computer scientists
and all that they came up with this
algorithm that works like a brain
you need a lot of data to train that and
you need a lot of processing power
because it's a very
long
and computer intensive process but
that's it deep learning is a way to
accomplish machine learning machine
learning is a way to accomplish ai all
right now deep learning is being used by
companies for example like google or
google or tesla for example because they
can process and have massive amounts of
data and they have massive amounts of
money so
how does a full stack programmer come up
and start working with machine learning
and deep learning well if you want to
get started in machine learning you have
to learn python that is like the best
way to get started if you know python
then you can move on and look into
something called tensorflow thankfully
you don't have to do all these things by
yourself manually you don't have to
create the neural networks by yourself
the community has already built tons and
tons of things the most popular
framework for artificial intelligence is
called tensorflow tensorflow is on
javascript and python so those two
languages are super super easy to get
started with and you can get started
tomorrow if you wanted to also there is
this thing called brain js on brain.js
they already have neural networks deep
learning algorithms
activation functions i'll cheat on the
things already done for you to work with
deep learning and node.js so if you ask
me it's an amazing thing like i said the
community has already built so many
things so if you're scared of math
calculus and all that you can go and
start playing around with tensorflow or
with brain.js and that will just give
you an introduction of what is machine
learning without having to take care of
all the math and the calculus python and
javascript those two languages are going
to be big big big big on machine
learning i think python already is it's
massive and javascript is starting there
because it's on the web
thank you for watching i hope that you
enjoyed this video
let me know what you think let me know
in the comments
just keep in mind that this concept is
for newbies and i'm not trying to be
super correct and specific in all the
things i say so if you think actually
that was wrong just remember that i'm
just trying to explain this into
the easiest terms icon let me know what
you think leave a like leave a comment
subscribe share to your friends and as
always don't forget to eat kimchi bye
bye
and you say everybody today we are going
to talk about apis uh this video is one
of the first videos of the series called
newbie questions
let's get started what is an api why so
many people talk about apis why are they
so important why does everybody have an
api whether it is a facebook api
instagram api
an api is just basically like this
keyboard like right here with this
keyword we interact with the computer
when i press a button here beautiful
button that i can i press this button
something happens inside of this
something happens inside of my computer
and that shows me the text on the screen
all right i'm interacting with the
computer
through the keyboard that's how i am
inputting information
with the keys that they have provided
this is the only way i can interact with
my computer now an api is something like
this
an api is how
do programs interact with each other an
api is made for code to be able to
interact with basically other code or
other technology an api is just
basically this keyword
that you make from your server and you
give that keyword to the ios application
boom
with this key you're going to log in
with this key you're going to log out
with this key you're going to upload a
photo with this key you're going to
follow somebody and when the ios or
android presses these keys that is going
to have an effect on the database
back there on your servers far away
that is basically an api now what is a
rest api what is a graphql api what is a
soap api what is an xml api these are
just different shapes of keyboards but
they accomplish the same thing they let
programs communicate with each other but
this is not the only api that you can
find you can also find public apis there
are weather weather apis which is a
server that has the weather of
everywhere in the world and when you
press the button get weather of korea is
going to show you that weather also we
have instagram api we have facebook apis
those are just keyboards that your
program can use to interact with those
applications with those servers now apis
are designed by the people that have the
server and that are making the api so
for example some apis they don't allow
you to do everything sometimes the apis
come with limitations sometimes you have
to pay for access to the keyword
sometimes you can only send maybe 10
requests per second there is another
kind of api which is for example the web
api web apis are apis
made for the browser for google chrome
for firefox for all that and those are
the same thing the the chrome team the
firefox team the safari team they all
buttons for you to use
every time there is a new button popping
up and before the api was really really
small like this small
only this part was the api but now it's
been growing so now we have buttons for
example that if i press this button i
can request access to the user
microphone if i play if i press this
button i can also request access to the
user camera if i press another button i
request access to the geolocation so
those are just buttons that you press
to
have some result you don't see the
internals of that job you don't see the
internals of how chrome is getting my
location you don't see the internals of
how firefox is getting my audio you
don't do any of that they just give you
a button and when you press it many
things happen under it but that's not
your problem and that's why everybody
loves an api they have different
purposes but they do the same thing they
just expose buttons that then you can
press with your code
and that will that will have some uh
result at the end so do you need an api
you don't need an api it depends on your
needs should you build an api out of
nowhere it depends on your needs should
you learn how to make an api of course
you should you can learn that in other
courses or everywhere in the world thank
you for watching i hope that you like
this tiny tiny explanation let me know
what other newbie questions you have i
would love to answer them on the
comments or on another video and that's
it again thank you and i will see you on
the next one
don't forget as always
eat kimchi bye
and today we are going to talk about why
domains cost money when you pay for a
domain why do you have to pay for that
com and where is that money going what
is the domain factory and what would it
take if i want to create a new domain
like for example that kimchi so to
understand this first we need to learn
how the domain system works
websites are just computers connected to
the internet and the way computers find
each other is by the ip address and the
ip address is just a very long series of
numbers but it will be very very
inefficient if instead of me saying hey
go to nomadcollege.com i would say
something like go to
192.168. that will be really really bad
so what we came up with to fix this
problem is something called the domain
name system the domain name system is
basically a big phone book that has the
address of your website and then their
ip address so when you go to google.com
on your browser your browser will ask
that phone book
google.com ip address and then you will
be taken to that ip address now the
thing is it will be very very bad and
inefficient if we only had one phone
book because there are millions of
domain names so actually what happens is
not that there is one phone book that
knows everything but there is one phone
book that knows who knows what that
means is that when you go to google.com
you're going to go and ask to the root
phone book of all and then you will say
hey where is google.com and they will
say
we don't know where google.com is but we
know who knows and they send you to that
that place where they send you is also
another phone book and this is called a
registry and registries are run by
private companies in this case for
example the dot com registry is run by a
company called verisign which is one of
the biggest companies four domain names
running a registry is not an easy job
but it's a very profitable one a
registry basically has to handle all the
connections of maybe servers asking them
where is youtube.com where is google.com
where is all the that comes this is
their job they have to have the
infrastructure they have to have the
bandwidth they have to have the security
all that stuff and as you can imagine
there are many many tiny other books for
example that co is another registry that
code.kr is another registry that tv is
another registry all these are
registries remember registries are just
books with the address
and the ip so registries are the domain
factories they are the ones with the
books that come here that come here they
know this but they don't sell the
domains to the public for example if you
want to buy a domain right now you don't
go to verisign you go to one of the
domain resellers so godaddy let's say is
a domain reseller and when you go to
godaddy you pay them a little bit more
of what that dot com domain cost for
example in the case of verisign that com
domain cost 7.5 from them but if you go
right now to godaddy or whatever the
company you are going to pay more than
7.5
this is because the people that you are
buying the domain from are the middlemen
and they handle the users the password
the support the renewing all that stuff
they handle that and that's why you have
to pay them so for example if you buy a
dot com domain from me you will pay me
let's say 30
i take 30
i thank you very much and i pay 7.5 to
verizon and verisign will add your
domain to the list now how can i create
my own registry because maybe i want to
have a new domain and i want to say you
know what i want to sell that dimgy
domains the way you can create your own
domain and the way you can run your own
registry is by applying to the i can the
icon is an organization that handles all
these domain things and they are the
ones that sort of hold the key of the
big and main root domain so for example
if i say hey can you please put me there
in the dark kimchi so if somebody asked
you that kimchi then you point them to
me this is the icon and the application
cost 185
000 and you need to prove that this
domain will improve the internet you
also need to prove that you have the
technology you have the customer support
you have the infrastructure and you have
the money to be able to support
questions to your registry because
having a registry is not an easy job as
i said you're going to have a lot of
questions of people asking you where is
i love that kimchi where is it
these things cost money but the thing is
that once you have your own registry you
can do almost whatever you want with the
domain you can choose to sell them or
maybe not sell them so for example i can
say i will only sell that kimchi domains
if you are a hangout salam and you enjoy
kimchi that could be
my choice or for example some people
have domains like that new york city
that nyc and they can say yo only people
that live here can buy this domain so
send me a copy of your address and you
will be able to buy this domain it's
very very interesting is the main thing
also because it's a very very good
business like i said the dot com domain
is run by a company called very signing
verisign is very very profitable they
also run the domain.tv the domain.tv is
assigned to the country of tuvalu but
because they have a deal verizon is the
one keeping the registry of the that tv
domain and thanks to this to value is
getting two million dollars a year only
on royalties from the that tv domain and
that's like 10
of their whole income so it's a very
very good business this is all very very
public you can go to the website and you
can see exactly who runs a domain that
academy who runs a domain that's sexy
because now anybody can apply because
the icon opened applications long time
ago and now you can apply for any domain
you want that is that sexy that baby
that academy that consultant that
whatever and you can go and see exactly
who is the one running what so very
interesting stuff but now you know the
domain factory is the registry a
registry is just a phone
book if you want to become one of those
phone books you have to pay a lot of
money and you have to have the
infrastructure but it is a very very
good business and that's why they keep
doing it and they're even more remember
when you pay for a domain name you are
not paying directly to the registry you
are paying for the middle man the
middleman is the one handling the
contract with you the renewal the credit
card processing and all that stuff okay
that's it for this video let me know
what you think on the comments thank you
so much for watching your support your
comments your liking for being here and
listening to what i have to say don't
forget to be happy don't forget to eat
kimchi thomas amida shannon hill bye
what is it what are the good parts what
are the bad parts and who should be
using it
serverless is changing the way that we
build applications and how we design
backends but there seems to be some
confusion around what serverless
actually is and this is because of the
name
server less literally means without a
server so people think that serverless
means back-ends without servers and that
would be impossible because you still
need a server the code has to go
somewhere so serverless doesn't mean
back-ends without servers it actually
means something more like
back-ends without managing your own
servers it's longer and it doesn't sound
so sexy so that's why i guess they chose
server less to understand the problems
that serverless solves first we need to
understand how we used to deploy
applications before you had to go to the
store and buy your own server and put it
in your living room and plug it in by
yourself and this meant that you had to
manage the software and the hardware of
the server so if for example your house
had a problem with the energy your
server was down or if somebody unplugged
the cable your website just went dead or
if your website was too popular and you
had too many users and the memory of
your server wasn't big enough you had to
run to the store and buy a memory and
put it in your server you had to do it
all manually by yourself in your living
room
then on the 2000s amazon came with a
product called ec2 elastic compute cloud
and now instead of having a server in
your living room you can just pay amazon
and rent a space on a server that they
control and that they take error so now
you don't have to worry about anybody
plugging out the cable or the energy
going down or your server not being big
enough because with amazon you can just
pay for more storage and they will just
add more storage they will add more
memory to your server we are renting a
space on a server in amazon or google or
microsoft they are the ones keeping the
lights on and taking care of all the
hardware related issues but still we
need to manage the software of our
server we are just renting an empty
server somewhere we have to put the
software on that server
and managing software can be very
challenging because you need to keep up
with the os updates or security patches
or database backups or failure recovery
systems or many many things that come
with managing server software and this
is when serverless comes in
[Music]
with serverless you don't upload a
backend to a server with serverless you
break your back-end into small little
functions and you upload those functions
to a server that you don't control on
something for example like aws lambda
and this is the big big difference about
serverless and non-servers on
non-serverless your server is always on
24 7 ready to answer for requests
on serverless the functions you upload
are sleeping
and the moment that they get a request
aws for example will wake the function
up the function will wake up the
function will do the job and then the
function will go to sleep again
and that is the revolutionary concept
about serverless that it doesn't have to
be on 24 7 and that makes it really
really cheap on traditional servers if
for example you have 0 users or 100
users you are still paying rent
on serverless you only pay for an
execution of your function this means
that if you get a request and your
function wakes up you start paying if
the function finishes and the function
goes to sleep again
you stop paying and this makes it really
really cheap for example the aws lambda
prices are incredibly cheap you can get
1 million executions for only 20 cents
that's insane
this also allows you to scale
better because that means that if you
get a lot of users for example suddenly
you have 1000 users what aws will do is
that it will just wake up a thousand
copies of the same function and once
those users are gone those functions
will go to sleep and you are not going
to have to pay more and the performance
of your website is not going to be
affected because if you get more users
you create more functions and it keeps
going like that
[Music]
so what are the not so good parts about
serverless and there are two in my
opinion the first one is called cold
starts like i said your functions are
going to be asleep
and that means that when you get a
request there has to be some time a
little bit of time that we're gonna take
for the function to wake up and start
working and this can take a little bit
of time not so much but a little bit it
will take longer than in a normal server
because a normal server is always on and
ready to go a serverless function is not
on all the time it's asleep and it has
to wake up
to start working and that can take
milliseconds it's not very very slow
it's just milli milliseconds but some
companies really care about milliseconds
so maybe serverless wouldn't be a good
fit for them having said that aws lambda
for example has many ways of knowing
which function is popular so it doesn't
go to sleep completely and it keeps it a
little bit ready to reply in case it
gets more users so it isn't a big deal
but it can still add some milliseconds
to the time your server answers the
number two thing not so good about
serverless is that basically you are
marrying your cloud provider if for
example you deploy a serverless backend
to aws you are basically marrying
aws and if you have a fight with aws you
cannot just take your functions and go
to a different cloud provider because
migrating from serverless provider to
serverless providing it's not an easy
process
is easier if you just rent a server
space on aws and you want to go to a
server space on google cloud but
serverless wise the company has
different ways of doing things so
migrating will be a little bit more
painful the architecture of an
application will be changed when you
work on serverless because you need to
get into any mindset of you don't
control your server anymore but once you
know how to work with that and once you
figure out ways of doing that then is
very very rewarding
[Music]
so who should work with serverless i
would recommend serverless to anybody
that has a side project or a company
that is starting and is working and
trying to get a prototype out as soon as
possible serverless allows you to work
on the code and not to worry on the
configuration and it's really really
easy to get an idea out there using
serverless if you basically don't want
to spend so much time configuring
servers and caring about all that stuff
then serverless is the way serverless is
a tradeoff you can finish products
faster configure less and pay less
because it's super super cheap but you
will lose control over your server and
you have to modify the architecture as
always server is not going to replace
the traditional way of doing back-ends
but it's nice to have more tools as full
stacks to finish the products faster if
you want to get started with serverless
go and check out the awesome serverless
framework at serverless.com
or aws lander google cloud functions
apex or terra form these are the ones
that i've been looking at and i'm very
interested in serverless because i
really like the fact that i don't have
to pay anything to put my code somewhere
so that's it for this video let me know
what you think of serverless are you
going to try it have you tried it what
are you doing with it i'm very
interested in serverless myself and i
hope i can build something with it soon
thank you for watching leave a like
leave a comment tell your friends and as
always don't forget to be happy don't
forget to eat kimchi kansam nida
and bye